Dhaka, Bangladesh alienpapon009@gmail.com (880) 1625 - 997661

Rathijit Paul

linkedin.com/in/rathijitpapon009/ github.com/rathijitpapon www.rathijitpaul.com

I'm a software developer with 1 year of experience. I'm passionate about solving problems, writing efficient codes & developing software tools that will increase people's productivity. Currently, I'm a senior undergraduate student with a Computer Science & Engineering background.

Work Experience

Junior Software Engineer

Free Pixel Games Ltd.

Feb 2021 - Present

Development team

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Reduced Analytical Decision Making Time by developing various game data analytics tools.
- Improved Game Tools' Performance by implementing efficient algorithms and techniques.
- Improved Revenue Generation by continuously giving analytical reports based on user data.
- Developed web apps for showing games' ads to users worldwide.
- Developed many other internal tools, APIs & modules for the company.

Software Engineer Intern

Mainframe Labs Ltd.

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

Development team

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Modularized Complex System by developing user microservice that serves user functionalities to the whole system.
- Reduced Processing Time by developing an OMR scanning tool that calculates MCQ results from formatted scripts.
- Contributed to a website's frontend collaborating with the design team.
- Learned lots of new technologies, industry-standard good practices & team collaborations in software development.

Education

• B.Sc. Computer Science & Engineering, Bangladesh University of Engineering & Technology 2017 – Present

Technologies and Languages

• Languages: Javascript, Python, C++, Java, MySQL, MongoDB

• Technologies: React.Js, Node.Js, Angular, Git, Docker

• Skills: Data Structures & Algorithms, Web Development, Problem Solving, Competitive Programming

Projects

Line Of Action:

React.Js | Javascript | Minimax

Developed a web-based game called the line of action. It's a part of my academic project which intends to implement Al-based games using some heuristic algorithms. See the source codes of Github.

Travel Talk:

React.Js | Node.Js | REST API | MongoDB | Websocket

Developed a full-stack web application called the Travel Talk which intends to make a social platform for travelers worldwide. See the source codes of Frontend & Backend.

Online Judge:

Java | JavaFX | FTP

Developed a java-based FTP application along with a teammate where users can submit the source code for the programming problems & in response the server gives them a verdict like accepted or error. See the source codes on Github.